Guide to the Miner Searle Bates Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Other Notes and Collected Material, Series V
  - Mixed Format Notes and Collected Material
    - Topics
      - Church and State - International Missionary Council Tambarum Conference, 1938 (Box 112, Folder 948)
      - Colombia (Box 112, Folder 949)
      - Communism and the U.S.S.R. Bibliographies, handwritten notes (Box 112, Folder 950)
      - Communism and the U.S.S.R. Papers (Box 112, Folder 951)
      - Communism and the U.S.S.R. Typescript notes, documents (Box 112, Folder 952)
      - European history (Box 112, Folder 953)
      - Fascism (Box 112, Folder 954)
      - Hiking (Box 112, Folder 955)
      - Hiking (Box 113, Folder 956-957)
      - India (Box 113, Folder 958)
      - Information about miscellaneous individuals (Box 113, Folder 959-960)
      - Indonesia (Box 113, Folder 961)
      - Japan - handwritten notes (Box 113, Folder 962)
      - Japan - typescript notes and documents, re. Sino-Japanese conflict (Box 113, Folder 963)
      - Japan - typescript notes and documents, miscellaneous (Box 113, Folder 964)
      - Japan - printed material (Box 113, Folder 965)
      - Kagawa, Toyohiko (Box 113, Folder 966)
      - Korea (Box 113, Folder 967)
      - Latourette, Kenneth Scott (Box 113, Folder 968)
      - Middle East (Box 114, Folder 969)
      - Missions bibliography (Box 114, Folder 970)
      - Missions theory - handwritten notes (Box 114, Folder 971)
      - Missions theory - typescript notes (Box 114, Folder 972)
      - Missions theory - typescript papers and documents (Box 114, Folder 973)
      - Missions theory - printed material (Box 114, Folder 974)
      - Race (Box 114, Folder 975)
      - Religious liberty - handwritten notes (Box 114, Folder 976)
      - Religious liberty - typescript notes and documents (Box 114, Folder 977-978)
      - Religious liberty - printed material (Box 114, Folder 979-980)
      - Religious liberty - printed material (Box 115, Folder 981-983)
      - Roman Catholic Church and missions (Box 115, Folder 984)
      - Sermon notes and prayers (Box 115, Folder 985-986)
      - South America (Box 115, Folder 987)
      - South Pacific (Box 115, Folder 988)
      - Taiwan (Box 115, Folder 989)
      - Theological education (Box 115, Folder 990)
      - Theology (Box 115, Folder 991)
      - United Nations (Box 115, Folder 992)
  - Addendum
    - Maps of China (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Hand-drawn maps of China; political divisions in different eras (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Maps of Nanking (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Maps of Shanghai, Taipei (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlet and map: "Operations of Indian Expeditionary Force "D" 1914-1917" (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Contract between the University of Nanking and Chen Yu-Meng, 1925 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Chinese language notes (Box 132, Folder 7)
- Writings, Series VI
  The writings of Series VI are divided into five sections:
  Articles, pamphlets, papers - arranged alphabetically by title
  Book reviews - arranged chronologically
  Reports and memoranda from China - arranged chronologically
  Sermons, addresses, interviews - arranged chronologically
  Related to major works - arranged alphabetically by title with appropriate subheadings
  - Articles, Pamphlets, Papers
    - "Africa in Christian Perspective", n.d. (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Africa Tests Christian Understanding," Christianity and Crisis (hereafter C C), 1959 Apr (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Africa: Unrecognized Diversity," C C, 1958 Mar (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Aftermath of Registration of Refugees at the University, 26 December 1937", 1938 Jan (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "An American in China," Virginia Quarterly Review, 1955 (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Angola: A Candle in the Gloom of Violence" (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Asia: Its Needs and Possibilities" (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Authority in the New Testament", 1924 Jun (Box 85, Folder 659)
    - "Barometer of the Far East," C C, 1956 May (Box 85, Folder 660)
    - "Beyond American Comforts and Tariffs`" C C, 1970 Oct (Box 85, Folder 660)
    - "A Call to Action," National Christian Council Review, 1952 Nov (Box 85, Folder 661)
    - "Candles Flicker in South Africa" (Box 85, Folder 661)
    - "Candles in the Chasms" (Box 85, Folder 661)
    - "China," in The Prospects of Christianity Through out the World, 1963 (Box 85, Folder 661)
    - "China", n.d. (Box 85, Folder 661)
    - "China: A Plea for Courage and Light, C C, 1957 Mar (Box 85)
    - "China and Her Asian Neighbors," C C, 1966 Jun (Box 85)
    - "China and International Communism," C C, 1963 Feb (Box 85)
    - "China and Vietnam," C C, 1967 Jun (Box 85)
    - "China as a Model for Asian Revolutions: and Perhaps for African and Latin American as Well" (Box 85)
    - "China Cannot Be Ignored," C C, 1960 Oct (Box 85, Folder 662)
    - "China Consultation 1962," N.C.C.C., U.S.A. (Box 85)
    - "China in a New Context," C C, 1972 Aug (Box 85)
    - "China in Conflict: Soothsayer's Quandary," C C, 1967 Feb (Box 85)
    - "China is Just Too Large to Ignore", n.d. (Box 85, Folder 663)
    - "China is Still There," C C, 1968 Mar (Box 85)
    - "The China Issues in Perspective", 1961 Oct (Box 85)
    - "A China Miscellany" (bibliography), Missionary Research Library, 1971 Dec (Box 85)
    - "China 1958: The Manufacture of a Society," C C, 1959 Jan (Box 85)
    - "The China Question: A Plea for Courage and Light" (Box 85)
    - "The China Question: Who Settled What?", late 1960s (Box 85)
    - "China: Revolution Against Revolution?," C C, 1967 Oct (Box 85, Folder 666)
    - "China: The Human Scene," C C, 1965 Apr (Box 85)
    - "The China Vote," C C, 1962 Jan (Box 85)
    - "The Chinese Church and the World Church," Bulletin of the International Missionary Council, 1945 Nov (Box 85, Folder 665)
    - Commentary on "Europe's Crisis and America's Dilemma" by K. W. Thompson, C C, 1957 Jan (Box 86, Folder 671)
    - "Communism and the Christian Response" (Bibliography), Missionary Research Library, 1956 Aug (Box 86)
    - "Confound Their Politics, Frustrate Their Knavish Tricks," C C, 1957 Nov (Box 86)
    - "Confucian Ethics", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Congo Disciples: A Visitor's Reflections", 1954 Apr (Box 86)
    - "Contact with Churches in China, C C, 1957 May (Box 86)
    - "Contemporary American Opinion of the Monroe Doctrine", 1926 (Box 86, Folder 672)
    - "Contemporary Challenges to Freedom," C C, 1958 Jul (Box 86)
    - "The Continuing Sino-Soviet Dispute," C C, 1963 Sep (Box 86)
    - "The Crisis of Missions in China and Southeastern Asia," Christian World Facts, 1942 Feb (Box 86)
    - "Crop Investigation in the Nanking Area and Sundry Economic Data" (Report prepared for the Nanking International Relief Committee), 1938 Oct (Box 86)
    - "Crude Sabotage of Considered Policy: Aid to Yugo slavia and Poland," C C (Box 86)
    - "A Cup of Cold Orange Juice," C C, 1957 Oct (Box 86)
    - "Data on the Distribution of the Missionary Enter prise," International Missionary Council, 1943 (Box 86, Folder 673)
    - "Dangerous Thoughts Regarding China (or, American Attitudes Toward China)", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Day After Tomorrow in the Orient," World Call, 1942 May (Box 86)
    - "Democracy in Japan", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Development of Ministers--A Major Issue in Missions", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Diagnosis of the Present Disorder - Regional Statement for Asia," W.C.C., 1947 Sep (Box 86, Folder 674)
    - "The Disciple Commitment to Church Union", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Disciples Missions in the Ecumenical Framework", 1954 Aug (Box 86)
    - "Distressed China - The Legacy of War," World Call, 1946 Nov (Box 86)
    - "Divided China," C C, 1946 Sep (Box 86)
    - "Does Tibet Matter?" C C, 1959 May (Box 86, Folder 675)
    - "The Drama Presses On" (Published in Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury ), 1936 Oct (Box 86)
    - "Drama Near Tragedy" (leading editorial in Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury ), 1936 Oct (Box 86)
    - "'East' and 'West' at Evanston," C C, 1954 Nov (Box 86, Folder 676)
    - "East Asia: A Christian Reminder," C C, 1951 Jan (Box 86)
    - "Education and Equalitarian Drives in the Chinese'Cultural Revolution"' (Box 86)
    - "The Effects of Western Contacts upon the Political Life of China", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "The Chinese Factor in World Rivalries," C C, 1970 Feb (Box 85, Folder 665)
    - "The Chinese Revolution: Phase 1969," C C, 1969 Jul (Box 85)
    - "The Chinese Role in International Communism", n.d. (Box 85)
    - "The Chinese Sector, 1964," C C, 1964 Feb (Box 85, Folder 666)
    - "The Chinese State and Religion, with Particular Reference to Christianity, 1840-1949" (Columbia University Seminar on Modern East Asia), 1967 Nov (Box 85)
    - "The Christian Churches in China Today", 1965 Jan (Box 85, Folder 667)
    - "Christian Concern for Black Africa," C C, 1953 Jul (Box 85)
    - "Christian Concerns in African Politics," C C, 1958 Jun (Box 85)
    - "Christian Historian, Doer of Christian History. In Memory of Kenneth Scott Latourette 1884 1968," International Review of Missions, 1969 (Box 85)
    - "The Christian Mission in Nanking", 1941 Feb (Box 85)
    - "Christian Missions in This Weary World," The Christian-Evangelist, ca.1933 (Box 85)
    - "The Christian Movement in China," World Call, 1942 Jan (Box 85)
    - "The Christian Movement in China Meets the Tests of War", 1941 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - "The Christian Movement in China: Troubled Glory, Anxious Faith," Motive, 1942 Nov (Box 85, Folder 667)
    - "Christian Prospects in China", 1949 Apr (Box 85)
    - "Christian Service in War Torn China", n.d. (Box 85)
    - "Christian Work in China: The Economic and Political Background", 1947 Oct (Box 85)
    - "Christian Youth and Today's World," World Call, 1942 May (Box 85)
    - "Christianity and Social-Economic Issues" (Lectures given at National Student Secretaries Reading Party at Hangchow), 1937 Jan (Box 85, Folder 668)
    - "Christianity in China Today," World Call, 1941 Jul-Aug (Box 85)
    - "Christianity in the Peoples' Republic of China", n.d. (Box 85)
    - "Christianity in the People's Republic--A Time for Study to Understand" (Box 85)
    - "A Christian's Select Bibliography on Communism," Missionary Research Library, 1961 Nov (Box 85)
    - "Church and State," in Twentieth Century Encyclopedia of Religious Knowledge, ca. 1951- 1953 (Box 85, Folder 669)
    - "The Church in China: Current Phase," C C, 1943 Sep (Box 85)
    - "The Church in China in the Twentieth Century", ca. 1967 (Box 85)
    - "The Church Must Still Help China," The Christian Century, 1942 Apr (Box 86, Folder 670)
    - "Church, State and Citizen in Italy," C C, 1958 May (Box 85)
    - "Churches and Christians in China, 1950-1967: Fragments of Understanding," Pacific Affairs, 1968 (Box 85)
    - "The Churches and the United Nations," C C, 1952 Feb (Box 85)
    - "The Churches and the United Nations" (Box 85)
    - "A Delegation of Japanese Christians in China", n.d. (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - "The Effort and the Measure of Success Attained By Missions in Attempting to Adapt Their Work to Chinese Culture and Society", 1960 Apr (Box 86, Folder 676)
    - "Evangelism and Missions at Evanston,", 1954 Nov (Box 86)
    - "The Experience of Liberation: A Voice from Nanking," World Call, 1946 Mar (Box 86)
    - "Explanatory Comment on Luther Shao's Accusation and 'Self-Criticism"', 1951 (Box 86)
    - "Eyes on the Orient" series for World Call, 1941-1945, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 677)
    - "The Far East and Missionary Planning," International Review of Missions (Box 86, Folder 678)
    - "The Far East Draws Near" (outline), n.d. (Box 86)
    - "The Far East from Within/Oriental Views of the Far East/Japanese Rule in Occupied Territories", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "The Far East: Test of Western Capacity for Brother hood," C C, 1942 Oct (Box 86)
    - "Far Eastern Missions in Crisis", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "The Fate of Christianity in China," C C, 1968 May (Box 86)
    - "Food for China?" C C, 1961 Apr (Box 86, Folder 679)
    - "Fumbling for a China Policy," Commonweal (?), 1968 (Box 86)
    - "Ghana in Christian Focus", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Half of Humanity: Far Eastern Peoples and Problems," The Church Peace Union, 1942 (Box 86)
    - "Heard in the Gates," Shane Quarterly (lectures delivered at Butler University), 1951 Apr (Box 86, Folder 680)
    - "How Protestantism Began in Latin America", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "How Will the War End for Japan?" Far Eastern Survey, 1942 Jul (Box 86)
    - "International Missionary Council," in Twentieth Century Encyclopedia of Religious Knowledge, ca. 1951 1953 (Box 86)
    - "The International Scene: Good Society or Class Struggle", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "Is There a New Russian Since Stalin? C C, 1957 Nov (Box 86)
    - "Is There an Africa?", n.d. (Box 86)
    - "The Issues in Church Relationships," N.C.C.C., U.S.A., 1958 (Box 87, Folder 681)
    - "Japan", n.d. (Box 87, Folder 682)
    - "Japan and China: A War of Minds," Pacific Affairs, 1937 Sep (Box 87)
    - "The Japanese Treaty Settlement," C C, 1950 (?) (Box 87)
    - "Japan's Great Adventure", 1937 Nov (Box 87)
    - "Kenneth Scott Latourette: Major Informant on China", 1969 (Box 87, Folder 683)
    - "Korea", n.d. (Box 87)
    - "Kuomintang" in Encyclopedia for Social Science, n.d. (Box 87)
    - "League of Nations, The Churches and the" in Twentieth Century Encyclopedia of Religious Knowledge, ca. 1951- 1953 (Box 87, Folder 684)
    - Letter to the editor of North China Daily News, 1938 May (Box 87)
    - Letter to the editor of Evening Post, 1939 Dec (Box 87)
    - "Lights and Shadows in Nanking", 1927 (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - "Love Must Tool Up for the Emergency", 1942 Mar (Box 87)
    - "Mao the Forthright Enigma," C C, 1970 Apr (Box 87)
    - "Mao Victor or Victim? Which Mao?" C C, 1969 Jan (Box 87)
    - "The Marxian Interpretation of History", n.d. (Box 87, Folder 685)
    - "Materials on Problems of State and Church in the Far East", 1939 (Box 87)
    - "Memorandum for Robert F. Smylie", 1971 Jun (Box 87)
    - "Missionary" in World Book Encyclopedia, 1976 (Box 87)
    - "A Missionary Journey -- War Model 1940" (Box 87)
    - "Missions in Far Eastern Cultural Relations" Institute of Pacific Relations, 1942 (Box 87, Folder 686)
    - "Missions in the Far Eastern War," The Christian Evangelist, 1942 Feb (Box 87, Folder 687)
    - "Missions in the Whole Life of the Church", 1942 Jan (Box 87)
    - "Missions in War," The United Christian Missionary Society, n.d. (Box 87)
    - "Missions in War Emergency," World Call, 1942 Feb (Box 87)
    - "Moral Demands of Collective Security," C C, 1952 Nov (Box 87)
    - "Mr. Nehru's Himalayan Blunder," C C, 1962 Dec (Box 87)
    - "The Nanking Population: Employment, Earnings and Expenditures" (survey prepared for the Nanking International Relief Committee), 1939 (Box 87, Folder 688)
    - "The Narcotic Problem," The Chinese Recorder, 1940 Oct (Box 87)
    - "Narcotics in Nanking," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, 1939 Nov (Box 87)
    - "The National Government," China Christian Year Book, 1931 (Box 87, Folder 689)
    - "The National Government," China Christian Year Book, 1932-1933 (Box 87)
    - National/Public/Social Affairs series from China Mission News Letter (see also: China Mission News Letter, Record Group 31), 1935-1950,n.d. (Box 87, Folder 690)
    - "Needed--a Strong African Ministry," World Call, 1954 Jun (Box 87, Folder 691)
    - "New Light in South Africa", n.d. (Box 87)
    - "Not One China or Two, But Six," C C, 1955 May (Box 87)
    - "Notes on Technical Method in Christian Publication Programs", n.d. (Box 87)
    - "Notes on the Choice of Institutions for Training U.C.M.S. Candidates for Foreign Service, with Especial Reference to Disciple Seminaries", 1945 Feb (Box 87)
    - "Old China and New Militarism," World Call, 1937 May (Box 87, Folder 692)
    - "O'Neill vs. Blanshard: Review of Catholicism and American Freedom," C C, 1952 Jun (Box 87)
    - "An Open Letter on the Narcotic Problem," Shanghai Evening Post, 1938 Nov (Box 87)
    - "The Orient is - Folks", 1944 Jul (Box 87)
    - "Our Commitment to Church Union," The Christian Evangelist, 1956 May (Box 87)
    - "Out of This World? But We Can't Get There", n.d. (Box 87)
    - "The Outlook for Christianity in China", 1949 Apr (Box 87)
    - "Peking's Understanding of the World and Its Destiny", 1965 Sep (Box 87, Folder 693)
    - "Persecution and Toleration" in Encyclopedia Americana, 1964 Feb (Box 87)
    - "Policy Crisis in Catholic Colombia," The Christian Century, 1954 Jun (Box 87)
    - "PRC--USA--USSR," C C, 1971 May (Box 87)
    - "Problems of Religious Liberty: Mid-Century Phases", 1966 (Box 87)
    - "Public Affairs", 1940 (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - "Queries on U.S. Policy in South and East Asia," C C, 1955 Oct (Box 88, Folder 694)
    - "Rays of Hope in South Africa," C C, 1962 Apr (Box 88)
    - "Realism in the United Nations," C C, 1956 Jan (Box 88)
    - "Recent Literature in Missions," The Chaplain, 1959 Feb (Box 88)
    - "Reconstruction and Christian Opportunity", 1943 Nov (Box 88)
    - "Relief and Rehabilitation in China," The Christian Evangelist, 1945 Jan (Box 88)
    - "Religious Liberty" in Twentieth Century Encyclopedia of Religious Knowledge, ca. 1951 1953 (Box 88, Folder 695)
    - "Religious Liberty" in Encyclopedia Americana, 1963 (Box 88)
    - "Religious Liberty - Church and State," Missionary Research Library, 1959 Jul (Box 88)
    - "Religious Liberty in China," International Review of Missions, 1946 (Box 88)
    - "Religious Liberty: Recent Phases of the Problem", n.d. (Box 88)
    - "Religious Liberty: The Roman Catholic Factor," Pulpit Digest, 1959 Nov (Box 88)
    - "The Remaking of China", ca. 1933 (Box 88, Folder 696)
    - "Report from Outer Space: China," C C, 1963 Apr (Box 88)
    - "The Revolution in China, 1966 Model," C C, 1966 Oct (Box 88)
    - "The Rise of Modern Europe", n.d. (Box 88)
    - "The Secret of Chinese Resistance", n.d. (Box 88, Folder 697)
    - "A Select List of Books on Religious Liberty, Church and State (published 1945-1959)" (Box 88)
    - "The Sino-Soviet Dispute: Current Phase", n.d. (Box 88)
    - "Some Christian Concern in African Politics", n.d. (Box 88, Folder 698)
    - "Some Problems of African Christians," C C, 1954 Jan (Box 88)
    - "Some Recent Contributions in Thought and Effort on Behalf of Religious Liberty" (Box 88)
    - "Some Reflections on 1925 and 1975 and the Years Between" (Box 88)
    - "Some Thoughts on India and Nehru" (Box 88)
    - "Statement on Religious Freedom", 1943 Jul (Box 88)
    - "Straits That Are Desperate", n.d. (Box 88)
    - "The Strength of Mao's Power," C C, 1969 Feb (Box 88)
    - "Study in the World Christian Mission," Union Seminary Quarterly Review, 1951 Jan (Box 88)
    - "Suez and Colonialism," C C, 1956 Oct (Box 88, Folder 699)
    - "Suggestions for the Settlement of Peace in the Far East", 1943 Jun (Box 88)
    - "The Sun Will Rise Again in the East," World Call, 1942 Aug (Box 88)
    - "Survey of the Training of the Ministry in Africa," International Missionary Council, 1954 (Box 88)
    - "Survey of the Training of the Ministry in Africa," Daystar, 1954 Oct (Box 88)
    - "Symposium on China: Toward Understanding China and the Chinese People," N.C.C.C., U.S.A., 1968 (Box 88, Folder 700)
    - "The Task of Education in China," Pacific Affairs, 1946 (Box 88, Folder 701)
    - "That Other Congress - the One in Moscow", n.d. (Box 88)
    - "Toward the Understanding of Chinese Politics 1931 1932," Pacific Affairs (Box 88)
    - "Toynbee as Historian," C C, 1955 Mar (Box 88)
    - "The Training of Christian Ministers in Non-British Africa," International Review of Missions, 1954 (Box 88, Folder 702)
    - "Traitors to Whom?" C C, 1957 Mar (Box 88)
    - "Treason to the Rulers or to the People?", n.d. (Box 88)
    - "Two Decades of Revolutionary China," C C, 1969 Oct (Box 88)
    - "The United States and China. Stalin and J.McCarthy Are Gone", 1968 May (Box 89, Folder 703)
    - "Vietnam, Geneva and China" (Box 89)
    - "A Voluntary Group Under Communist Rule: The Christians" (Columbia University Seminar on Modern East Asia), 1961 Oct (Box 89, Folder 704)
    - "Wanted for African Export: Durable Saints," Union Seminary Quarterly Review, 1954 Mar (Box 89, Folder 705)
    - "The War and Missions," World Call, 1941 Oct (Box 89)
    - "War Poverty: Nanking", ca. 1940 (Box 89)
    - "War Relief in Nanking", 1933 Apr (Box 89)
    - "Wartime Achievements of the Christian Church in China," Christian Laymen, 1942 Feb (Box 89)
    - "What About China?" World Call, 1944 May (Box 89)
    - "What Are Missionaries Really Doing?", n.d. (Box 89)
    - "What Is the Future of the Missionary Program in China?", 1925-1928 ? (Box 89)
    - "What Happened in Madras", ca. 1938 (Box 89)
    - "What's Happening in China?" C C, 1971 Feb (Box 89, Folder 706)
    - "What's the Score in China's Cultural Revolution?", 1968 Sep (Box 89)
    - "Who and What Is China?" (Box 89)
    - "Why Not an Embassy at the Vatican?", n.d. (Box 89)
    - "The World and Formosa," C C, 1953 Mar (Box 89)
    - "World Council as Seen at Evanston," C C, 1954 Sep (Box 89)
    - "World Mission Today and its Recent Literature," The Chaplain, 1959 Apr (Box 89)
    - "The Yale-in-China Association: Forty Years in the Life of China", n.d. (Box 89, Folder 707)
    - "'You Cannot Fool All of the People'--It's True in China, Too", n.d. (Box 89)
    - "The Younger Churches: Ghana 1957-58," The Christian Evangelist, 1958 Mar (Box 89)
    - Fragments / Unidentified (Box 89, Folder 708-709)
    - Untitled report, ca. 1939 (Box 132, Folder 12)
  - Book Reviews
    - By MSB, 1928-1974, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 710-716)
  - Reports and Memoranda from China
    - Various, 1927, 1928 (Box 90, Folder 717)
    - Including the following: Memorandum on Policy Toward Japan (1935); Report on Present Day Japan (1936), 1935, 1936 (Box 90, Folder 718)
    - Including: Report on Japan (1937), 1937-1938 (Box 90, Folder 719)
    - Various, 1939-1941, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 720)
  - Sermons, Addresses, Interviews
    - See also: Two folders of fragmentary sermon notes and prayers in Series V., 1925-1974, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 722-734)
  - Related to Major Works
    - "The Establishment of the Centralized Empire in China, 221-87 B.C." (Ph.D. Dissertation, Yale, 1935): Abstracts (Box 91, Folder 735)
    - Dissertation - Chinese Language Material, notes (Box 91, Folder 736)
    - Religious Liberty: An Inquiry (1945): Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 91, Folder 737)
    - Religious Liberty: An Inquiry (1945): Correspondence, 1947-1970 (Box 91, Folder 738)
    - Religious Liberty: An Inquiry (1945): Publicity and distribution, 1944-1950 (Box 91, Folder 739)
    - Religious Liberty: An Inquiry (1945): Reviews (Box 91, Folder 740)
    - Religious Liberty: An Inquiry (1945): Reviews, 1946 (Box 91, Folder 741)
    - Religious Liberty: An Inquiry (1945): Reviews, 1947-1948, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 742)
    - China in Change: An Approach to Understanding (MSB, editor, 1969) Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 92, Folder 743)
    - China in Change: First draft, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 744)
    - China in Change: Final draft, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 745)
    - China in Change: Re. Chapter 1, by H. Boorman, 1967-1968 (Box 92, Folder 746)
    - China in Change: Re. Chapter 2, by C. M. Wilbur, 1967-1968 (Box 92, Folder 747)
    - China in Change: Re. Chapter 3, by T. Chen, 1967 (Box 92, Folder 748)
    - China in Change: Re. Chapter 4, by C. Buss, 1967-1968 (Box 92, Folder 749)
    - China in Change: Re. Chapter 5, by W. C. Merwin (Box 92, Folder 750)
    - China in Change: Re. Chapter 6, by E. B. Copland (Box 92, Folder 751)
    - China in Change: Re. Conclusion, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 752)